theclassifieds.co.za 2012-12-29

# Privacy Policy - TheClassifieds - South Africa - Free Classifieds in South Africa - TheClassifieds, South Africa's Classifieds Website - Post Free Ads in South Africa

1\. Introduction

**1.1** **TheClassifieds** recognises the importance of protecting the personal information that you ("the User") provide to us. Therefore, we have put together, and endevour to follow this policy that respects and addresses that.

2\. Information collection

**2.1** **TheClassifieds** collects information from the User at several different points on the Site. **TheClassifieds** is the sole owner of the information collected on **TheClassifieds** 's web site ("the Site"). We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement.

**2.2** Consent to collect information can be express (eg. signing an agreement) or implied (eg. if the User is given an opportunity to opt-out of a specific form of information sharing, but chooses not to do so, **TheClassifieds** implies that the User chooses to share this information with us).

**2.3** **TheClassifieds** processes personal information on web hosting servers which may not be in your present country.

3\. Information we collect

**3.1** In the course of service provision to the User we may collect certain forms of information. The types of information that we may collect are detailed below:

**3.1.1** Information you provide - When you place a classified on **TheClassifieds** by completing the appropriate form, we ask you for personal information (such as your name, email address and phone number). We may combine the information you submit under your account with information from other services or third parties in order to provide you with a better experience and to improve the quality of our service.

**3.1.2** Cookies - When you visit **TheClassifieds** , we may send one or more cookies - a small file containing a string of characters - to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service by storing user preferences or storing session information. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, this is not advised as some features (and indeed our service itself) may not function correctly if your cookies are disabled.

**3.1.3** Log information - When you use **TheClassifieds** , our server automatically records information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser.

**3.1.4** User communications - When you send email or other communication to **TheClassifieds** , we may retain those communications in order to process your enquiries, respond to your requests and improve our services. 

**3.1.5** Links - **TheClassifieds** may present links in a format that enables us to keep track of whether these links have been followed and who followed them, either on the web site or in electronic communications. We use this information to improve the quality of our service, customized content and advertising.

**3.1.6** Other sites - This Privacy Policy only applies to **TheClassifieds**. We do not exercise control over any third party sites who we have partnered with to deliver a service to you. These other sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you, over which **TheClassifieds** has no control.

4\. How this information is used

**4.1** **TheClassifieds** collects user information for the purposes described below:

**4.1.1** Providing a service to our users, including the display of customized content and advertising

**4.1.2** Auditing, research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our service

**4.1.3** Ensuring the technical functioning of our equipment and resources

**4.2** While mostly this information will be used to provide a service to our users, it may also be used to provide our own services.

**4.3** We will not collect or use sensitive information for purposes other than those described in this Privacy Policy unless we have obtained your prior consent. 

5\. Communications

**5.1** **TheClassifieds** may send the User, site and service announcement updates on an irregular basis. Users are not able to unsubscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about our service.

**5.2** On occasion **TheClassifieds** will email newletters to provide the User with information that we think the User will find useful, including information about new products and services. We might also contact the User by email to see if the User is interested in participating in market research regarding **TheClassifieds**. We may also contact the User by email to respond to customer-service complaints that the User has submitted, to address a problem affecting the Userâ€™s use of the service or to verify the Userâ€™s account information if the User submits a password request.

6\. Information Sharing

**6.1** **TheClassifieds** may share aggregate demographic information with our advertisers or information collection companies, but will not reveal any personally identifiable information in these instances. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. We may also partner with third parties to provide specific services. When the User signs up for these services, we will share the information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. These parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services.

**6.2** We will not voluntarily disclose any information about individual users, except as described in this Privacy Policy, or to comply with applicable laws or valid legal process, or to protect the rights or property of **TheClassifieds** or others, to assist our email vendor with resolving complaints about unsolicited email, or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy.

7\. Data Integrity

**7.1** **TheClassifieds** processes personal information only for the purposes for which it was collected and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. We review our data collection, storage and processing practices to ensure that we only collect, store and process the personal information needed to provide or improve our services. We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we process is accurate, complete, and current, but we depend on our users to update or correct their personal information whenever necessary and possible.

8\. Information Security

**8.1** We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. The servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment.

**8.2** We restrict access to personal information to **TheClassifieds** employees who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our services.

9\. Acquisition or Merger

**9.1** It is possible that **TheClassifieds** and/or any of our assets may be acquired in an acquisition or a merger. In such a transaction, customer information may be transferred to the acquiring entity. While we will endeavour to require the successor company to maintain this Privacy Policy, we cannot guarantee that this policy will remain in effect after such a corporate action.

10\. Notification of Changes

**10.1** This policy may be revised over time as new features are added to the Web site and/or as changes are required due to changing circumstances. We will post our new Privacy Policy, along with the date of its last revision, prominently so that the User will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and whether we will disclose it to anyone.

**10.2** **TheClassifieds** is, however, under no obligation to inform the User of such changes when they happen, although it is assumed that any changes will be minor and will not fundamentally impact the User. Should the change be deemed by **TheClassifieds** to be significant, we will endevour to inform the User of these changes through whatever means we deem necessary (banner on home page, email notification etc.) in a timely manner.

11\. Contact Information

**11.1** If the User has any questions about this Privacy Statement or about **TheClassifieds** 's information collection practices, please contact us at [info@TheClassifieds.co.za](mailto:info@TheClassifieds.co.za?Subject=Privacy%20Policy)

12\. Terms

**12.1** The terms "The User" and "User" are used interchangeably and refer to all individuals and/or entities accessing this web site for any reason whatsoever.

**12.2** The terms "we" and "TheClassifieds" are used interchangeably and refer to **TheClassifieds** itself and all individuals and/or entities acting directly on behalf of **TheClassifieds**.
